LinkedIn European Regional Privacy Notice
=========================================

On November 3, 2025, we updated this notice to provide information about our reliance on Legitimate Interests as the legal basis for training content-generating AI models used in our products. You can opt out any time in your [settings](https://www.linkedin.com/mypreferences/d/settings/data-for-ai-improvement) if you’d prefer not to have your data used in this way﻿[](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a7152512)

_[Effective August 21, 2026](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1341216/updates-to-user-agreement-and-privacy-policy)_

This European Regional Privacy Notice (this “Notice”) supplements LinkedIn’s [Privacy Policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy) and contains additional information for Members and Visitors located in the Designated Countries (as defined in the Introduction to the [Privacy Policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy)) and the United Kingdom. If there is a discrepancy between the [Privacy Policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy) and this Notice, the information in this Notice will apply to you. Unless otherwise indicated below, the information in this Notice applies to members in both the Designated Countries and the UK.

#### **Data Controller**

As set out in our [Privacy Policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy), if you are located in the Designated Countries, LinkedIn Ireland Unlimited Company with its address at Wilton Place, Dublin 2, Ireland, is the data controller of your personal data. If you are located in the United Kingdom, LinkedIn Corporation with its address at 1000 W Maude Avenue, Sunnyvale, CA, is the data controller of your personal data. When we refer to “**LinkedIn”** in this Notice we mean LinkedIn Ireland Unlimited Company or LinkedIn Corporation, as it applies to you.

#### **Legal bases for processing your personal data**

LinkedIn only processes your personal data when we have a legal basis. We set out in this section each of the legal bases we rely on, why and how we use your data, and the categories of personal data we process.

#### **To perform our contract with you**

LinkedIn processes personal data when it is necessary to perform our contract (the [User Agreement](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/user-agreement)) with our Members. Where we need your personal data to perform a contract with you and you do not provide the data, we will not be able to enter into the contract, or we may have to suspend or cancel any existing contract we have with you.  

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| **Why and how we use your data** | **Data we use** |
| To allow Members to register for and manage access to their LinkedIn account, to view the LinkedIn platform in their preferred language, and to receive the core Services under our User Agreement. | Your account information: your name, email address, [login](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1335211?hcppcid=search) and [two-step verification](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1358878?hcppcid=search) information, [payment information](https://www.linkedin.com/help/billing/answer/a1340105) (for paid Services), subscription information, and Member-chosen language.<br><br>Data relating to your use of our Services: IP address, device ID, user agent, location data, browser type and version, operating system and platform, and other online identifiers collected from [Cookies](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy) and other similar technologies. |

#### **Consent**

We may process your personal data with your consent. You can withdraw your consent by using your Member settings or by [contacting us](https://nam06.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.linkedin.com%2Fhelp%2Flinkedin%2Fask%2Fppq&data=05%7C02%7Cssundholm%40linkedin.com%7Cda78086e62bc43d9651708dcc759ec40%7C72f988bf86f141af91ab2d7cd011db47%7C0%7C0%7C638604436264149657%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C0%7C%7C%7C&sdata=KFnKedvcckZE6sfyxXqL%2FjkCdzKxwi%2B5WmejCVGH3Lk%3D&reserved=0).

LinkedIn processes personal data when Members give us consent, such as via their [Account and Privacy Settings](https://www.linkedin.com/mypreferences/d/categories/account), by agreeing to our terms, and through in-product experiences. Where we rely on consent, you can withdraw your consent at any time, however this will not affect our use of your data up to that point.  

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| **Why and how we use your data** | **Data we use** |
| So Members can add information to their profiles and display it to their connections, network and Visitors on LinkedIn, and display it off LinkedIn on their publicly-visible profile and in the applications of [Affiliates](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy#key-terms-1), partners, customers and developers. | Data that you or others provide in [your LinkedIn profile:](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a564064?hcppcid=search) your name, photo, current position, education, location, skills, endorsements, recommendations, and contact details |
| To enable two-factor authentication for Members to protect their LinkedIn accounts, or recover access to their LinkedIn accounts. | Two-factor verification information (e.g., phone number)<br><br>Name<br><br>Year of birth<br><br>City, state/province, country<br><br>ID type and issue<br><br>Redacted copy of ID, with only the full name and face portrait being visible |
| To allow Members to make and accept new connections. | Connect functionality on Member profiles<br><br>Contact information (email, telephone, etc.) |
| So Members can show their profile alongside information about their company or institution, or their stated interests on LinkedIn. | Data that you or others provide in [your LinkedIn profile](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a564064?hcppcid=search): your name, photo, current position, education, location, skills, endorsements, recommendations, and contact details |
| So that Members can verify certain information about themselves, to include a verification and related information on their profile and elsewhere where their profile information appears, and, depending on the verification method, to receive and store verification data, and to use it for security purposes. | Verification data (work or educational institution email address, profile verification badge and information, Member ID, hashed unique identifier, country of issuance for government IDs used to obtain verification badge via our verification partner)<br><br>LinkedIn profile name<br><br>Name from your government ID used to verify your identity<br><br>Phone number<br><br>Alternative names used by you (other than the name on your profile) to help us verify your identity |
| So Members can interact with our platform functionality, features and tools, such as certain tools and solutions that leverage AI. | Member inputted information (e.g., learning goals, topics of interest, uploaded CVs)<br><br>Publicly-viewable information on Members<br><br>Data that you or others provide in [your LinkedIn profile:](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a564064?hcppcid=search) your name, photo, current position, education, location, skills, endorsements, recommendations, and contact details |
| For LinkedIn or third parties to send Members marketing communications (e.g., emails or SMS messages) in order to market products, services and events. | Contact details (e.g., email address, phone number, InMail handle), location and current position<br><br>Other data submitted through Lead Generation Forms (e.g. name, company, answers to custom questions) |
| To enable Members to discover, signal interest in and apply for jobs and opportunities on LinkedIn; and to enable Members to be discovered by hirers for job and opportunities. | Location<br><br>Job search filters (e.g. industry, experience level, job type, remote status, salary, benefits etc.)<br><br>Job preferences (as set by Members), including "Open to Work"<br><br>Uploaded CVs<br><br>Member profile information submitted by Members as part of a job application<br><br>Job account information |
| For LinkedIn to use non-essential cookies and similar tracking technologies to identify Members, to deliver ads, and to conduct analytics related to user interaction with LinkedIn pages, advertising and research purposes. | Data relating to your use of our Services: IP address, device ID, user agent, location data, browser type and version, operating system and platform, and other online identifiers collected from [Cookies](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy) and similar technologies |
| **For Personalised Ads in the Designated Countries:**<br><br>1\. To display, measure, and improve certain personalised (not contextual) ads on and off LinkedIn that are relevant to your interests, based on certain data we observe or infer about you from use of our Services.<br><br>2\. To target, measure, and improve certain personalised (not contextual) ads on and off LinkedIn based on data we obtain from third parties | **1\. LinkedIn Data**<br><br>Inferred City, Country and Continent Location (from your IP address)<br><br>Inferred Gender<br><br>Inferred Age Range<br><br>[Your activity data](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a546122?hcppcid=search): This is data that we observe over time about your engagement with our Services, such as company page visits, videos you watch, actions you take on ads (views and clicks) and your participation in events on LinkedIn.<br><br>Inferred Interests (e.g. your general, product and service interests) and Traits (e.g. that you are an expat, frequent traveler, job seeker) based on your LinkedIn profile and activity on LinkedIn<br><br>Data relating to your use of our Services: IP address, device ID, user agent, location data, browser type and version, operating system and platform, and other online identifiers collected from [Cookies](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy) and similar technologies<br><br>**2\. Off-LinkedIn Data**<br><br>Ad Partners Data for Ads off LinkedIn and ad measurement: IP addresses, cookies, as ID, other online identifiers, views and clicks<br><br>Advertiser Data for Ads: contact information (hashed email, name, ad ID), device information, visits, views and clicks.<br><br>Advertiser Data to Measure Ad Success: Visits, sign-ups, purchases.<br><br>Data relating to your use of third party services: IP address, device ID, user agent, location data, browser type and version, operating system and platform, and other online identifiers collected from [Cookies](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy) and similar technologies that customers share with LinkedIn<br><br>You can [learn more](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a7157083) about how LinkedIn uses data from others for ads.<br><br>You can [amend your settings](https://www.linkedin.com/mypreferences/d/categories/ads) at any time and learn more about [adjusting your settings](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1342443/).<br><br>You can [learn more](https://members.linkedin.com/en-gb/privacy-in-advertising) about the ad technologies we use, our advertising services and our advertising partners. |
| **For Personalised Ads in the UK:**<br><br>For LinkedIn and its customers to use data we receive form third parties to display personalised advertisements to Members and Visitors | Information from advertising [partners](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy#key-terms-2), vendors and [publishers](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/85809?trk=microsites-frontend_legal_privacy-policy&lang=en) (e.g., LinkedIn advertiser customers who install a LinkedIn [tag](https://www.linkedin.com/help/lms/answer/a427660/) on their websites)<br><br>[Learn more](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a426264/) about the ad technologies we use, our advertising services and our advertising partners<br><br>You can control how we use your personal data for this type of advertising [here](https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/advertising-data). |
| To tailor, measure and optimise ads when you choose to submit a Lead Generation Form or take part in a brand lift survey through our Services | Contact details (e.g., email address, first and last name, LinkedIn profile URL), and current position, company name, company size and industry<br><br>Other data submitted through Lead Generation Forms or surveys (e.g., name, company, answers to custom questions) |
| To perform analytics to provide aggregated workforce and salary insights to Members, customers and others based on Member-provided data. | Member provided demographic data (e.g. disability and gender) |

#### **Legitimate Interest**  

Where we rely on legitimate interests we balance the interests the processing supports against your rights and freedoms before processing your personal data, and you have the right to object or to ask for restriction of our processing we describe in this notice at any time.

#### **When does LinkedIn rely on legitimate interests?**

In some cases, the collection and processing of your personal data is based on our legitimate interests and/or the legitimate interests of third parties (e.g., LinkedIn customers and our Members), provided that our interest in processing does not outweigh your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms. These interests include commercial interests, the interests of our Members and broader societal benefits. In each instance, we have considered whether these interests are outweighed by your rights and freedoms, and have concluded, based on the limited impact of the processing, the strong safeguards we apply, and the controls we offer you over your data, that we can proceed with the processing.  

If you have questions about how LinkedIn processes your personal data, you can view our [Privacy Policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy), the many articles and resources on our [Help Centre](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin) or you can [Contact us](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/solve).  

|     | How we use your data | Legitimate interests relied on | Personal data used |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| **Safety and security:** | To help protect you, us,  or others from threats, we log users' activity on LinkedIn to identify and investigate harmful or fraudulent behaviour that violates our [User Agreement](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/user-agreement). Examples of the behaviour include: security threats, hacks, scraping, fake accounts and information, bots, malicious actors, or fraud.<br><br>To enforce LinkedIn's minimum age, as defined in our [User Agreement](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/user-agreement)<br><br>To verify certain information you have provided e.g. your workplace, educational institution or your identity.<br><br>To share data with our Affiliates including our parent company, Microsoft, for security purposes, to prevent, detect investigate and address possible fraud or harmful behaviour or other violations of the law or our User Agreement, attempts to harm our Members, Visitors, our Affiliates or others, and to protect the security and integrity of our site.<br><br>To share data with other organisations for security purposes to prevent, detect, investigate and address threats, harmful behaviour, possible fraud or other violations of the law.<br><br>To use automated systems such as generative AI to detect and prevent harmful content on your feed and in [messages](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1341705), and train and improve our AI systems for these trust and security-related purposes.<br><br>To verify your account following account restriction or closure for breaches of our User Agreement. | To improve the safety, security, authenticity of our Services.<br><br>To ensure the protection of children under 16 and the provision of adequate safeguards for 16 and 17 year olds on LinkedIn<br><br>To better protect the personal data of our Members and Visitors.<br><br>To detect, investigate and address threats, bad actors and malicious activity on LinkedIn.<br><br>So that our Affiliates, including our parent company, Microsoft, can detect, investigate and address threats, possible fraud, bad actors, harmful behaviour and malicious activity against LinkedIn, Microsoft, our Affiliates, and others.<br><br>So that LinkedIn and other organisations can detect, investigate and address threats, possible fraud, bad actors and malicious activity online. | Data relating to your use of our Services: IP address, device ID, user agent, location data, browser type and version, operating system and platform, and other online identifiers collected from [Cookies](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy) and other similar technologies<br><br>Your attestation that you are over or under the age of majority in your region, and if you are under the age of majority in your region, your date of birth<br><br>Your account information: your email address, [login](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1335211?hcppcid=search) and [two-step verification](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1358878?hcppcid=search) information, [payment](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1340156?hcppcid=search) and subscription information<br><br>Data that you or others provide in [your LinkedIn profile:](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a564064?hcppcid=search) your name, photo, current position, education, location, skills, endorsements, recommendations, and contact details<br><br>[Your activity data](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a546122?hcppcid=search): This is data that you or others provide in posts, comments, articles, or other content on our Services including search history, feed, content you read, content you share, who you follow or is following you, connections, participation, page visits, videos you watch, actions you take on ads (views and clicks) and your job searches<br><br>Data that you provide when you [contact us](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a518597?hcppcid=search) or [request support](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/solve) via email, our ticket system or live chat. This may include your name, email address, LinkedIn account details, phone number, payment information and the details of your query or issue<br><br>[Inferences we make about you](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1337820?hcppcid=search)<br><br>Your connections and group memberships<br><br>Reports from you, or reports that others make about you relating to possible violations of [LinkedIn's User Agreement](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/user-agreement) or [Professional Community Policies](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/professional-community-policies)<br><br>Your verification badge and verification information when you have verified certain information on the platform<br><br>Where permitted, [Government ID](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1342692) and other personal identification documentation for account recovery purposes |
| **Business administration**: | To enable or administer our business, such as for quality control, preparing consolidated reports on our business, and customer service.<br><br>To manage corporate transactions, such as mergers, acquisitions or sales.<br><br>To monitor the use of our Member and customer service offerings and perform analytics to produce reports on the effectiveness of our Member and Customer support services.<br><br>To perform analytics to produce reports and metrics on how our Services are used to help evaluate product performance, fix issues, improve and deliver our Services.<br><br>To understand and improve our business or customer relationships generally.<br><br>To make business and financial projections.<br><br>To [Transfer Member and Customer data](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1343190) to be processed and stored on LinkedIn Corporation's data centres in the US.<br><br>To create reports and metrics based on your use of our products, such as interactions with ads, to enable us to invoice our customers for our products and services, and to understand usage of our Services. | To run our business efficiently and effectively.<br><br>To comply with laws regarding business operations, consumer protection and tax compliance.<br><br>To fulfil the expectations of our Members, Visitors, and customers about the high quality of our Services.<br><br>To enhance, grow, strengthen and otherwise manage our business and assets.<br><br>To meet the needs of our Visitors, Members and Customers, and better ensure that our Members, customers and Visitors receive quality services from LinkedIn. | Data relating to your use of our Services: IP address, device ID, user agent, location data, browser type and version, operating system and platform, and other online identifiers collected from [Cookies](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy) and other similar technologies<br><br>Your account information including payment and subscription information<br><br>Data that you provide when you [contact us](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a518597?hcppcid=search) or [request support](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/solve) via email, our ticket system or live chat. This may include your name, email address, LinkedIn account details, phone number, payment information and the details of your query or issue<br><br>Information received by post at any of our LinkedIn offices worldwide<br><br>Data that you or others provide in [your LinkedIn profile:](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a564064?hcppcid=search) your name, photo, current position, education, location, skills, endorsements, recommendations, and contact details<br><br>[Your activity data](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a546122?hcppcid=search): This is data that you or others provide in posts, comments, articles, or other content on our Services including search history, feed, content you read, content you share, who you follow or is following you, connections, participation, page visits, videos you watch, actions you take on ads (views and clicks) and your job searches<br><br>Your connections and group memberships<br><br>[Inferences we make about you](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1337820?hcppcid=search)<br><br>[Personal demographic data](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1336543)<br><br>Reports from you, or reports that others make about you relating to possible violations of [LinkedIn's User Agreement](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/user-agreement) or [Professional Community Policies](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/professional-community-policies)<br><br>Data about your use of some of the other services provided by us or our Affiliates, including [Microsoft](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1397243?hcppcid=search) |
| **Personalising your LinkedIn experience:** | To perform analytics (excluding for personalised ads purposes) and to personalise content and recommendations LinkedIn uses information you've provided, and information inferred from you and your network to personalise content and recommendations. LinkedIn may use profiling techniques to achieve these purposes. These include seeing posts and people that we think might interest you on your LinkedIn feed.<br><br>To make suggestions for how you can [expand your network](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a544682?hcppcid=search) by [recommending connections](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a544682?hcppcid=search), [groups](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a540824?hcppcid=search) and topics you may like to follow or [contribute](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1413111?hcppcid=search) to.<br><br>To [recommend jobs](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a512279?hcppcid=search).<br><br>To provide personalised features to customers in LinkedIn subscription services such as LinkedIn Premium.<br><br>Allowing LinkedIn Customers to search for and contact Members that may be interested in purchasing products or services<br><br>To allow LinkedIn customers to search for and contact Members that may be interested in purchasing products or services.<br><br>To allow LinkedIn customers to search for job candidates who match their job criteria and contact Members directly about job opportunities. | To fulfil our mission to connect the world's professionals to make them more productive and successful.<br><br>To create economic opportunity for our Members, customers and Visitors.<br><br>To enable our Members and Visitors to make real world connections with each other, find jobs and economic opportunity, express opinions, exchange information, and conduct business.<br><br>To meet LinkedIn's customers' interests in ensuring they can advertise jobs, products or services to Members who may be interested in them.<br><br>To provide Members with access to business development opportunities derived from B2B marketing.<br><br>To connect Members with jobs and opportunities to match their skills, experience and career aspirations. | Data relating to your use of our Services: IP address, device ID, user agent, location data, browser type and version, operating system and platform, and other online identifiers collected from [Cookies](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy) and other similar technologies<br><br>Data that you or others provide in [your LinkedIn profile:](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a564064?hcppcid=search) your name, photo, current position, education, location, skills, endorsements, recommendations, and contact details<br><br>[Your activity data](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a546122?hcppcid=search): This is data that you or others provide in posts, comments, articles, or other content on our Services including search history, feed, content you read, content you share, who you follow or is following you, connections, participation, page visits, videos you watch, actions you take on ads (views and clicks) and your job searches<br><br>Your connections and group memberships<br><br>[Inferences we make about you](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1337820?hcppcid=search)<br><br>[Personal demographic data](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1336543) |
| **Law enforcement and legal requests:** | To disclose information about you when required by law, subpoena, or other legal process or if we have a good faith belief that disclosure is reasonably necessary for any of the following reasons:<br><br>\- To investigate, prevent or take action regarding suspected or actual illegal activities or to assist government enforcement agencies;<br><br>\- To enforce our agreements with you and our customers;<br><br>\- To investigate and defend ourselves against any claims and allegations, including third-party claims;<br><br>\- To protect the security or integrity of our Services (such as by sharing with companies facing similar threats);<br><br>\- To exercise or protect the rights and safety of LinkedIn, our Members, personnel or others. | To advance the legitimate interests of LinkedIn and our wider community (including Members, Visitors and customers) to comply with the law.<br><br>To avoid sanctions for non-compliance.<br><br>To better protect against illegal or harmful activity in connection with our Services. | Data relating to your use of our Services: IP address, device ID, user agent, location data, browser type and version, operating system and platform, and other online identifiers collected from [Cookies](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy) and other similar technologies<br><br>Data that you or others provide in [your LinkedIn profile:](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a564064?hcppcid=search) your name, photo, current position, education, location, skills, endorsements, recommendations, and contact details<br><br>[Your activity data](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a546122?hcppcid=search): This is data that you or others provide in posts, comments, articles, or other content on our Services including search history, feed, content you read, content you share, who you follow or is following you, connections, participation, page visits, videos you watch, actions you take on ads (views and clicks) and your job searches<br><br>Your connections and group memberships<br><br>Your communications with LinkedIn, including information received by post at any of our LinkedIn offices worldwide |
| **Legal advice and litigation:** | We retain and share information with our lawyers and relevant experts when we seek legal advice or are involved in litigation. regulatory inquiries or disputes. | LinkedIn's interest to protect LinkedIn and its Affiliates, their brands, employees and business interests from legal challenges, regulatory investigations or criminal activity.<br><br>To better protect the interests of our Members, Visitors and customers by identifying and addressing illegal, unfair or harmful activity. | Any data relating to you that is relevant to the legal advice, possible litigation or ongoing litigation. This will depend on the nature of the legal issue and could involve any information related to your use of LinkedIn's products and the Services |
| **Research, development, statistics/insights and addressing errors:** | To review our products, conduct research and introduce new product features that help us better serve our Members and customers.<br><br>To generate metrics to understand how our Services are used, to inform and improve product direction and development. For example, we may measure how many users visit a certain page, how long they stay, or what actions they take on that page.<br><br>To undertake testing to evaluate the impact of new features.<br><br>To invite you to take surveys or provide feedback and analyse your responses to gain insights into users' views, preferences, needs, or experiences with our Services and to identify corrections and/or improvements for our products.<br><br>To produce aggregate insights to deliver data to Members, advertisers, and others relating to global workforce trends, to measure and improve equality of e.g. job opportunities.<br><br>To provide access to third party researchers who may conduct research regarding online safety and other areas where LinkedIn is required to allow access to certain data.<br><br>To identify and report aggregated trends like talent migration, hiring rates, and in-demand skills by region using [LinkedIn's Economic Graph](https://www.linkedin.com/showcase/linkedin-economic-graph/). | To help us connect people to economic opportunity in new ways and by partnering with governments and organisations around the world.<br><br>To fulfil our mission to connect the world's professionals to make them more productive and successful.<br><br>To create economic opportunity for our Members and Visitors.<br><br>To understand how people use our Services and what new features they like, so we can improve existing features and create more useful products in the future.<br><br>In furtherance of our legal and other obligations to provide safe, secure, fair and legal service. | [Personal demographic data](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1336543?hcppcid=search)<br><br>Your connections and group memberships<br><br>[Inferences we make about you](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1337820?hcppcid=search)<br><br>Data that you or others provide in [your LinkedIn profile:](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a564064?hcppcid=search) your name, photo, current position, education, location, skills, endorsements, recommendations, and contact details<br><br>[Your activity data](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a546122?hcppcid=search): This is data that you or others provide in posts, comments, articles, or other content on our Services including search history, feed, content you read, content you share, who you follow or is following you, connections, participation, page visits, videos you watch, actions you take on ads (views and clicks) and your job searches<br><br>Data relating to your use of our Services: IP address, device ID, user agent, location data, browser type and version, operating system and platform, and other online identifiers collected from [Cookies](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy) and other similar technologies |
| **For Personalised Ads in the Designated Countries:**<br><br>**1\. To display personalised ads:**<br><br>**2\. Use of personal data you give to us to perform and provide ads analytics and insights** | 1\. For personalised ads (including improving our ad tools) that are relevant to your interests, based on data from your LinkedIn profile and limited data we infer about you.<br><br>To display certain ads that are relevant to your interests and preferences, based on the data we collect from our Services.<br><br>To show you ads while you visit websites or apps on the LinkedIn Audience Network.<br><br>2\. To measure ad performance so that we can create aggregated reports (that don't identify you) for our customers on the performance and effectiveness of their ads and other informational promotional activities on our Services, and the professional characteristics of the audiences they reach.<br><br>So that we can bill and invoice our customers for our ad services and provide them with details about their advertising spend and return on investment, and support their ad budget management.<br><br>To identify members who have viewed an ad and consented to receive surveys so that our customers can measure the impact of an ad.<br><br>To monitor and prevent as fraud and inauthentic traffic; validate accuracy of ad measurement reporting, to support our internal ad site operations, and for LinkedIn's internal financial and operational business reporting. | 1\. To advance our mission to connect the world's professionals and to make them more productive and successful.<br><br>To enable our members to build their professional networks, and help them pursue professional and economic goals by offering more targeted, personalised and relevant ads to our members.<br><br>To generate income which enables LinkedIn to continue to operate its business. This also enables LinkedIn to provide its services for free to members, which is in LinkedIn's interests and also those of our members.<br><br>To support our advertising customers' interests in advertising jobs, products or services to members that are likely to be interested in them. This enables them to conduct and grow their business.<br><br>To support the interests of LinkedIn members as a whole by enabling and assisting LinkedIn members to: (i) access and provide services, (ii) assemble and associate, (iii) express themselves, including imparting and receiving information, (iv) educate themselves, (v) choose an occupation, engage in and move for work; and (vi) establish and conduct business.<br><br>To support general public interests including (i) support members advance professionally by creating opportunities for skills development and employment, and helping job-seekers and employers find each other; (ii) supporting effective and efficient labour markets; (iii) supporting the free movement of workers; and (iv) supporting innovation and knowledge-sharing in the economy.<br><br>2\. To help our customers measure and improve the impact and relevance of their ads, and to provide them with information about the types or categories of professionals they want to connect with.<br><br>To assist our customers in assessing the value of our advertising Services.<br><br>To generate income which enables LinkedIn to continue to operate its business. This also enables LinkedIn to provide its services for free to members, which is in LinkedIn's interests and also those of our members. | 1\. Data that you provide in [your LinkedIn profile](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a564064?hcppcid=search): your connections, companies you follow, education, job information, employer, skills, profile location, as well as the profile data provided by members that "look like" you, i.e. have similar professional profile attributes.<br><br>Skills derived from your profile<br><br>You can [amend your choices](https://www.linkedin.com/mypreferences/d/categories/ads) at any time.<br><br>You can [learn more](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a7400852) about our legitimate interests.<br><br>2\. Data relating to your use of our Services: IP address, device ID, user agent, location data, browser type and versions, operating system and platform, and other online identifiers collected from [Cookies](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy) and other similar technologies.<br><br>Data that you or others provide in [your LinkedIn profile](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a564064?hcppcid=search): your connections, companies you follow, education, job information, employer, profile location<br><br>Data about [actions you took in response to ads](https://www.linkedin.com/help/lms/answer/a420536) on LinkedIn: Ad impressions, dwell time on an ad, ad clicks, video, ad full views.<br><br>You can [learn more](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a7156194) about our ads measurement and reporting.<br><br>You can [amend your choices](https://www.linkedin.com/mypreferences/d/categories/ads) at any time.<br><br>You can [learn more](https://members.linkedin.com/en-gb/privacy-in-advertising) about the ad technologies we use, our advertising services and our advertising partners. |
| **To display personalised ads and for ads analytics and insights if you are in the UK** | To display certain ads that are relevant to your interests, based on the data we collect from our Services.<br><br>To show you ads while you visit websites or apps off LinkedIn. | To advance our mission to connect the world's professionals and to make them more productive and successful.<br><br>To enable our members to build their professional networks, and help them pursue professional and economic goals by offering more targeted, personalised and relevant ads to our members.<br><br>To generate income which enables LinkedIn to continue to operate its business. This also enables LinkedIn to provide its services for free to members, which is in LinkedIn's interests and also those of our members.<br><br>To support our advertising customers' interests in advertising jobs, products or services to members that are likely to be interested in them. This enables them to conduct and grow their business.<br><br>To support the interests of LinkedIn members as a whole by enabling and assisting LinkedIn members to: (i) access and provide services, (ii) assemble and associate, (iii) express themselves, including imparting and receiving information, (iv) educate themselves, (v) choose an occupation, engage in and move for work; and (vi) establish and conduct business.<br><br>To support general public interests including (i) support members advance professionally by creating opportunities for skills development and employment, and helping job-seekers and employers find each other; (i) supporting effective and efficient labour markets; (iii) supporting the free movement of workers; and (iv) supporting innovation and knowledge-sharing in the economy | Data that you provide in [your LinkedIn profile](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a564064?hcppcid=search): your connections, companies you follow, education, job information, employer. skills (that you or others provide about you), profile location<br><br>[Your activity data](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a546122?hcppcid=search): This is data that we observe over time about your engagement with our Services, such as company page visits, videos you watch, actions you take on ads (views and clicks) and your participation in events on LinkedIn, as well as the profile data provided by members that "look like" you, i.e. have similar professional profile attributes.<br><br>[Inferences we make about you](https://Inferences%20we%20make%20about%20you) including your city, country and continent based on IP address, your age range and gender, and inferred interests and traits<br><br>Actions by Members with similar profiles to yours<br><br>Third party requests to show ads to LinkedIn Members<br><br>Data relating to your use of our services, such as IP address, device ID, user agent, location data, browser type and versions, operating system and platform, and other online identifiers collected from [Cookies](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy) and other similar technologies<br><br>You can [amend your choices](https://www.linkedin.com/mypreferences/d/categories/ads) at any time<br><br>[Learn more](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a426264/) about the ad technologies we use, our advertising services and our advertising partners. |
| **To count ad clicks and conversions** | To perform ads measurement of conversion counts and value for business reporting purposes and to demonstrate the performance of our ads services to ads customers. | To advance our mission to connect the world's professionals and to make them more productive and successful.<br><br>To support our understanding of our advertising business and its effectiveness, allowing us to improve our business as a whole and advance our mission.<br><br>To support our advertising customers' interests in: (i) understanding the effectiveness of their advertising campaigns, and (ii) advertising jobs, products or services to members that are likely to be interested in them, This enables them to conduct and grow their business. | Data about [actions you took](https://www.linkedin.com/help/lms/answer/a420536) on LinkedIn: Ad impressions, dwell time on an ad, ad clicks, video as full views<br><br>Device information: App version, operating system<br><br>Conversion information from ads customers that does not identify you |
| **Our AI features generally:** | Members or customers may provide personal data as an input to an AI or [generative AI](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a5538339?hcppcid=search) feature ("AI-powered feature"), which could result in personal data being included within output. <br><br>Automatically processing your data (including your profile data and posts) as an input for an AI-powered feature (e.g. providing more relevant responses to your queries or in connection with your inputs to a generative AI feature).  <br><br>To power our [Hiring Assistant AI](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a7437598) features we process profile and resume data of Members to help hirers using our Recruiter and Jobs products review and source potential candidates including through matching job qualifications to Member data and providing AI generated summaries and explanations of a candidate potential match to a relevant position.<br><br>Using automated techniques, including generative AI-powered tools as part of our online safety and security efforts. | To enable economic opportunity and help our Members and customers be more productive and successful. <br><br>To enhance the safety and security of our platform.  <br><br>To improve the efficiency and effectiveness of providing our Services.  <br><br>To ensure that our products, features and Services are innovative, relevant and high quality.  <br><br>For our Hiring Assistant AI features:  <br><br>To make the recruiting and job seeking processes easier for customers and Members, which helps LinkedIn conduct its business more effectively.  <br><br>To enable our customers to organise information quickly and identify suitable candidates based on various criteria, benefiting Member job seekers by connecting them with relevant opportunities and broadening the candidate pool. <br><br>To provide economic opportunities for every member of the global workforce.  <br><br>So that Members can exercise their right to free movement for work.<br><br>So that Members can be discovered for appropriate job opportunities that match their skills and experience.<br><br>To increase access to the labour market and ensure that underrepresented groups with the required or desired skills are considered along with candidates who meet more traditional criteria. | Personal data manually input into an AI powered feature by Members  <br><br>Feedback you provide on AI features  <br><br>Data that you or others provide in a resume you provide or [your LinkedIn profile](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a564064?hcppcid=search):  your name, photo, current position and work experience, volunteer experience, education, location, skills, endorsements, recommendations, honours and awards, people and companies you follow, skills, patents, publications, licenses and certifications, recommendations, interests,  and contact details  <br><br>Your connections and group memberships  <br><br>Conversation data that users input into our GAI features (prompts, search text, queries, chats, responses, and other input and output data) <br><br>Member generated content (posts, articles, poll responses, contributions and comments) <br><br>For our Hiring Assistant AI features: LinkedIn profile data (the following sections, if complete): work experience, location, education, skills, summary, certifications and licenses, volunteering experience, publications, and patents. Your Open to Work status and preferences. Your resumes (if you have made them available). Responses to screening questions (if you have made them available).   <br><br>[Learn more](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a7437598) about our Hiring Assistants and how you can exercise your rights.  <br><br>Data relating to your use of our Services: IP address, device ID, user agent, location data, browser type and version, operating system and platform, and other online identifiers collected from  [Cookies](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy%22%20/t%20%22_blank)  and other similar technologies <br><br>[Inferences we make about you](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1337820?hcppcid=search%22%20\t%20%22_blank) <br><br>[Your activity data](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a546122?hcppcid=search): This is data that you or others provide in posts, comments, articles, or other content on our Services including search history, feed, content you read, content you share, who you follow or is following you, connections, participation, page visits, videos you watch, actions you take on ads (views and clicks) and your job searches  <br><br>[Learn more](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a5538339?hcppcid=search) about our use of your data for Generative AI. |
| **To offer our content-generating Generative AI features to Members** | To provide our Generative AI-powered Services to LinkedIn Members, including through Generative AI processing of the data described in the “Data used” column of this row to: <br><br>\- Suggest textual content to Members for those Members to use in a post or in their profiles.  <br><br>\- Prepare draft InMails or messages for Member or customer users to send.  <br><br>\- Create content that LinkedIn directly publishes on the platform (e.g., Collaborative Articles, Account IQ).  <br><br>\- Suggest advertising copy to LMS customers. <br><br>\- Provide chatbot conversations to assist Members and customers in completing a task. <br><br>If the output of the GenAI model is used for relevancy or ranking purposes, to: <br><br>\- Support relevancy, ranking, search, and similar functionalities on the LinkedIn platform. | To enable economic opportunity and help our Members and customers be more productive and successful. <br><br>To improve the efficiency and effectiveness of providing our Services.  <br><br>To ensure that our products, features and Services are innovative, relevant and high quality. | Data that you or others provide in [your LinkedIn profile](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a564064?hcppcid=search): your name, photo, current position and work experience, education, location, skills, summary, certifications, licenses, volunteering experiences, publications, patents, endorsements, and recommendations<br><br>[Your activity data](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a546122?hcppcid=search%22%20\t%20%22_blank): This is data that we observe over time about your engagement with our Services, such as company page visits, videos you watch, actions you take on ads (views and clicks) and your participation in events on LinkedIn <br><br>Conversation data that users input into our GAI features (prompts, search text, queries, chats, responses, and other input and output data) <br><br>Personal data manually input into an AI powered feature by Members  <br><br>Member generated content (posts, articles, poll responses, contributions and comments) <br><br>Feedback you provide on AI features  <br><br>Data relating to your use of our Services: IP address, device ID, user agent, location data, browser type and version, operating system and platform, and other online identifiers collected from [Cookies](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy%22%20/t%20%22_blank) and other similar technologies <br><br>[Inferences we make about you](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1337820?hcppcid=search%22%20\t%20%22_blank) |
| **To train our content-generating Generative AI systems** | To train, fine-tune, evaluate and improve our Generative AI models used to create content (textual, audio, visual, and other media, or multimedia) on the LinkedIn platform (or elsewhere) and in LinkedIn’s lines of business. Content creation includes:  <br><br>\- Suggesting textual content to Members for those Members to use in a post or in their profiles. <br><br>\- Preparing draft InMails or messages for Members or customer users to send (e.g., InBart (a LinkedIn GAI model), which was trained to create draft messages for recruiters). <br><br>\- Creating content that LinkedIn directly publishes on the platform (e.g., Collaborative Articles, Account IQ). <br><br>\- Suggesting advertising copy to LMS customers. <br><br>\- Responding to Member and customer prompts through a conversational assistant. | To provide and improve assistant experiences offered to LinkedIn members, customers, and others, enabling them to find economic opportunity and be more productive and successful. <br><br>To ensure that LinkedIn’s foundation models are fair, safe, accurate, and effective in the LinkedIn professional context. <br><br>To provide a conversational assistant to assist members for a variety of beneficial tasks on the LinkedIn platform and to promote an accurate, responsive, safe, and responsible experience for members and customers. | Data that you or others provide in [your LinkedIn profile](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a564064?hcppcid=search): your name, photo, current position and work experience, education, location, skills, summary, certifications, licenses, volunteering experiences, publications, patents, endorsements, and recommendations <br><br>\- Conversation data that users input into our GAI features (prompts, search text, queries, chats, responses, and other input and output data) <br><br>\- Group activity and group messages <br><br>\- Member generated content (posts, articles, poll responses, contributions and comments) <br><br>\- Responses to screening questions and resumes that members provide add to their LinkedIn account on  the LinkedIn platform for ongoing LinkedIn use <br><br>You can [opt out](https://www.linkedin.com/mypreferences/d/settings/data-for-ai-improvement) of our use of your data to train our content-generating AI models at any time.  <br><br>[Learn more](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a5538339?hcppcid=search%22%20\t%20%22_blank)  about our use of your data for Generative AI. |
| **To improve LinkedIn's products and Services generally** | To ensure our products and Services function as intended, to identify and resolve issues that may arise, and to evaluate the performance and reliability of new features, including gathering insights to inform product development, validating design assumptions, and understanding user preferences.  <br><br>To engage in research activities—such as user studies and feedback collection—to assess satisfaction and identify areas for improvement across our offerings and brand experience (including using Members' feedback to improve, correct or modify our Gen AI-powered features. <br><br>To train, pre-train, fine-tune, evaluate, and improve AI systems that support critical functions such as content classification, trust and safety enforcement, and security threat detection | To ensure that our products and Services function as intended. This includes monitoring performance, identifying technical issues, and implementing fixes to maintain a consistent and reliable user experience. <br><br>To develop and improve our offerings, including testing new features, evaluating their effectiveness, and iterating based on performance and user interaction to ensure our products remain competitive and relevant. <br><br>To align product development with user needs and expectations to help us deliver features that are meaningful and valuable to our members and customers. <br><br>To better understand how our products are used and perceived so that we can make informed business decisions and enhance our brand reputation. <br><br>To optimise internal operations, resource allocation, and long-term planning <br><br>To ensure the safety and security of our platform, products and Services. <br><br>To enhance the accuracy and reliability of our AI-driven moderation and classification tools to maintain trust and integrity. <br><br>To improve operational efficiency and product performance by refining AI systems that support scalable enforcement and compliance across our Services. <br><br>To foster innovation and economic opportunity by advancing AI capabilities that power professional tools and Services for our Members and customers. | Data that you or others provide in [your LinkedIn profile](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a564064?hcppcid=search): your name, photo, current position and work experience, education, location, skills, summary, certifications, licenses , volunteering experiences, publications, patents, endorsements, and recommendations <br><br>Conversation data that users input into our GAI features (prompts, search text, queries, chats, responses, and other input and output data)<br><br>[Your activity data](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a546122?hcppcid=search%22%20\t%20%22_blank): This is data that we observe over time about your engagement with our Services, such as company page visits, videos you watch, actions you take on ads (views and clicks) and your participation in events on LinkedIn<br><br>Your connections and group memberships<br><br>Your group activity and group messages<br><br>Member generated content (posts, articles, poll responses, contributions and comments)<br><br>Responses to screening questions and resumes that Members provide add to their LinkedIn account on the LinkedIn platform and for ongoing LinkedIn use<br><br>Feedback you provide on our Services (including about our AI powered features)<br><br>Data that you provide when you [contact us](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a518597?hcppcid=search%22%20\t%20%22_blank) or [request support](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/solve%22%20/t%20%22_blank) via email, our ticket system or live chat. This may include your name, email address, LinkedIn account details, phone number, payment information and the details of your query or issue<br><br>Data relating to your use of our Services: IP address, device ID, user agent, location data, browser type and version, operating system and platform, and other online identifiers collected from [Cookies](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy%22%20/t%20%22_blank) and other similar technologies<br><br>[Inferences we make about you](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1337820?hcppcid=search%22%20\t%20%22_blank)<br><br>Please see the "Objecting to the use of your data" section below for information on how to object to the use of your data for general product improvement purposes.<br><br>[Learn more](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a5538339?hcppcid=search%22%20\t%20%22_blank) about our use of your data for Generative AI. |
| **Direct Marketing:** | Where permitted, sending marketing [emails](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a517979?hcppcid=search) and other marketing communications about LinkedIn content, products or offers that we think will interest you. LinkedIn may use profiling techniques to achieve this purpose.<br><br>Promoting LinkedIn subscription services and other products and features we think you'd like on and off LinkedIn. | To enable economic opportunity and help our Members be more productive and successful.<br><br>To enhance and grow our business, meet the needs of our Visitors, Members and customers, and better ensure that our Members, customers and Visitors receive the quality services from LinkedIn. | Data that you or others provide in [your LinkedIn profile](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a564064?hcppcid=search): your name, photo, current position, education, location, skills, endorsements, recommendations, and contact details<br><br>[Your activity data](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a546122?hcppcid=search): This is data that you or others provide in posts, comments, articles, or other content on our Services including search history, feed, content you read, content you share, who you follow or is following you, connections, participation, page visits, videos you watch, actions you take on ads (views and clicks) and your job searches<br><br>Your email address<br><br>Your connections and group memberships<br><br>[Inferences we make about you](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1337820?hcppcid=search)<br><br>[Personal demographic data](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1336543)<br><br>Data relating to your use of our Services: IP address, device ID, user agent, location data, browser type and version, operating system and platform, and other online identifiers collected from [Cookies](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy) and other similar technologies |
| **If you are in the UK:**<br><br>Sharing data with our parent company, Microsoft for its AI training purposes | To share certain member data with Microsoft so that it can train, fine-tune, and evaluate, and otherwise improve Microsoft’s AI models. | To enable Microsoft to train AI models to produce fair, accurate, and relevant information that is reflective of the diversity of the communities in which AI models are deployed, and so that these models work just as well for all users.  <br><br>To enable Microsoft to improve its products and services for the benefit of its affiliates, including LinkedIn, and our members and customers. | Your posts, comments, articles, collaborative articles and LinkedIn video you create  <br><br>LinkedIn Learning Videos and Transcripts  <br><br>Company Page Data  <br><br>Job Postings <br><br>You can [opt out](https://www.linkedin.com/mypreferences/d/settings/data-for-ai-improvement) of our use of your data for this purpose any time. |

#### **Compliance with Legal Obligations**

LinkedIn processes information to comply with a legal obligation, such as preserving or disclosing certain information to adhere to a valid legal request from law enforcement agencies, courts or regulators, or to comply with financial or consumer law obligations. New legal obligations may arise over time requiring the processing of Member and Visitor personal data, below you can see examples of the types of obligations that apply to LinkedIn Ireland Unlimited Company. The data that we are required to process depends on e.g. the nature of the legal obligation or the legal request. See section 3.6 of our [Privacy Policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy) for more information.

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| **Applicable laws** | **Our legal obligations** |
| Civil and Commercial laws such as Regulation 2001/1206 on the Cooperation between the courts of the Member States in the taking of evidence in civil or commercial matters. | To comply with court orders requiring the processing of personal data. |
| Criminal laws such as the Criminal Justice (Theft and Fraud Offences) Act 2001. | To comply with search warrants and production orders requiring the processing of personal data. |
| Consumer laws such as the Competition and Consumer Protection Act 2014. | To comply with regulatory requests requiring the processing of personal data. |
| Company and Tax laws such as the Companies Act 2014. | To comply with regulatory requests requiring the processing of personal data. |
| Regulatory laws such as the General Data Protection Regulation, the Data Protection Act 2018, the ePrivacy Regulations. | To comply with regulatory requests or orders requiring the processing of personal data. |

#### **Public Interest**

LinkedIn will process personal data where it is necessary to carry out a task in the public interest e.g. to protect children from harm. Where we rely on this legal basis you have the right to object to our processing by using this [form](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/ask/TS-DPRO).

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| **Why and how we use your data** | **Data we use** |
| To detect and combat the spread of Child Sexual Abuse Material, LinkedIn analyses images and videos sent via messaging on our platform. | Images and video files content in Member messages. |

#### **Special Category Data**

LinkedIn does not encourage you to provide data that includes genetic, biometric and health data, or data revealing racial and ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or ideological convictions or trade union membership (“Special Category Data”) when using our Services. LinkedIn may process Special Category Data, based on our legitimate interests to provide our Services and for the benefit of our members and customers, on the basis of consent or, in certain cases, where such data has been manifestly made public.  

#### **If we have reason to believe you’re 16 or 17 years old** 

LinkedIn’s Privacy Policy and this Regional Privacy Notice apply, as they do for other members. You can **[Learn More](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a9490059)** about additional protections we seek to provide for members who we think may be 16 or 17 years old. 

#### **Data Sharing with Third Parties**

In addition to Section 3 of our [Privacy Policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy), we have set our further information below on how LinkedIn may share your personal data for specific purposes with its partners, third-party service providers, customers, regulators and law enforcement agencies, other services such as online search result tools, and our Affiliates including our parent company, Microsoft, and other LinkedIn entities.

#### LinkedIn Developer Programs

Participants in LinkedIn’s Developer Programs can access limited Member personal data via LinkedIn’s Talent, Marketing, Sales and Learning Solutions APIs under our partnership agreements.

#### Third Party Service Providers

LinkedIn may also share your data with third-party service providers and processors. These include our parent company, Microsoft, cloud service providers, content delivery networks, telecommunications providers, maintenance providers, Member support providers, ID verification providers, development service providers, market researchers, anti-fraud and anti-abuse services providers, marketing and analytics providers, payment processors, external auditors and advisors, managed services providers, consultancy and professional services firms, such as legal and tax advisors.

#### Regulators and Law Enforcement Agencies

In addition to the above, LinkedIn may also share your personal data with regulators and law enforcement agencies where it is required to do so by law. For more information on this, see section “**Compliance with Legal Obligations**” above.

#### Affiliates

_Our parent company_  

LinkedIn shares data with our parent company Microsoft, as set out in our [Privacy Policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy) and this Notice, to combat harmful or fraudulent behaviour, to protect the security and integrity of our site and the services of Microsoft and others, and, where permitted, so that Microsoft can train and improve its AI models (in accordance with [Microsoft’s privacy policies](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/privacy/privacystatement)).  

_LinkedIn Entities_  

LinkedIn Ireland Unlimited Company shares personal data of all of our Members and Visitors with LinkedIn Corporation in the United States for processing and storage at our data centres, and may share certain personal data with other LinkedIn entities for the LinkedIn group’s business and security purposes.  

With other organisations for safety and security  

We may also share personal data in order to protect the security or integrity of our Services (e.g. sharing examples of security or safety threats with other companies facing similar threats), or the rights and safety of LinkedIn, our Members, Visitors, and others.  

#### **How you can control your data**  

You can access, correct, rectify, delete your personal data, object to or ask us to restrict our processing or change your settings. You have many choices about how your data is collected, used and shared.

We offer a variety of ways for Members and Visitors to control their data. The easiest way to control how your data is processed if you are a Member is [via your account settings](https://www.linkedin.com/mypreferences/d/categories/account) and if you are a Visitor [via your Guest settings](https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/guest-controls). 

If you are a Visitor and you would like to contact LinkedIn about processing of your data or exercising the rights outlined in this section, you can reach out using the details in the “Contact Us” Section below or by using this [form](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/ask/TS-DPRO).

Members can also object, correct inaccurate data, delete data, port data and in some cases restrict the use of their data as set out in this section:

#### **Accessing your data**

Members can access and download their data at any time. We will provide your data in a structured readable format. You can start the download process from the Data Privacy section of your [Member Settings](https://www.linkedin.com/mypreferences/d/categories/privacy). You can learn more about how to download your data [here.](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1339364?hcppcid=search)

#### **Correct and rectify your data**

When Members are signed in to our platform you can always review and update your profile information. You can also ask us to change, rectify or not use your data if it is not accurate. You can edit or correct most of your personal data at any time directly in your account settings. If there is any personal data not listed in your account settings that you would like to correct or update you can [complete a data rectification form.](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/ask/TS-DRF) You can learn more about how you can change or correct your personal data [here](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1336621).

#### **Deleting your data**

You can request that we delete your personal data. Most of your profile data can be deleted [through your account settings.](https://www.linkedin.com/mypreferences/d/categories/account) You can learn more about deleting your data [here.](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1342613?hcppcid=search) For any data that cannot be deleted in your settings, you can submit a [Data Deletion request form](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/ask/TS-DDF). If you would like to delete all your personal data from LinkedIn, you can always choose to [close your account.](https://www.linkedin.com/mypreferences/d/close-accounts)

#### **Restricting the use of your data** 

One of the ways you can restrict how your data is used is in your [Data Privacy settings](https://www.linkedin.com/mypreferences/d/categories/privacy) and your [Advertising Data settings](https://www.linkedin.com/mypreferences/d/categories/ads). You can also request that processing of your data is restricted if the data is inaccurate or if you believe that the processing is unlawful by using the details in the “Contact Us” Section below or by using this [form](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/ask/TS-DPRO). 

#### **Objecting to the use of your data** 

You also have the right to object to processing your data where legitimate interest or public interest is the legal basis for processing that data. To exercise your right to object you can contact us by using the details in the “Contact Us” Section below or complete our [Data Processing Objection form](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/ask/TS-DPRO). 

Where you raise an objection, we will consider your request, our legal obligations, and whether we have a compelling interest in continuing to process your data. In certain cases, consistent with your legal rights and our obligations, we may not be able to fulfil your request—for example, we cannot stop processing your IP address when it is used to authenticate your login details, as this is a security measure that is essential to protect our site. In contrast, you can remove information about your education or work experience from your profile (although as a result, the job recommendations you receive may not be relevant to you) so that we don’t process it. 

Where we use your data for direct marketing (e.g. to send you marketing emails) or profiling for the purposes of direct marketing, you always have the right to object and we will stop using your data for this purpose.

#### **Portability** 

If we use your personal data to perform a contract with you, or with your consent, you have the right to receive your data and port it to another controller. You can download your data anytime in a structured readable format. You can start the download process from the Data Privacy section of your [Member Settings](https://www.linkedin.com/mypreferences/d/categories/privacy) and can learn more about how to download your data [here.](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1339364?hcppcid=search) LinkedIn also provides an [API program](https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/linkedin/dma/member-data-portability/member-data-portability-member) to enable third parties to build integrations with LinkedIn to port data on a Member’s consent in the EEA, EU and Switzerland only. You can find more details in the [Member Portability APIs](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a6214075) help centre article.

#### **Withdrawing your consent**

When you give us consent to use your personal data, you can withdraw that consent at any time. You can withdraw your consent via Member settings for certain processing, or by contacting us [here](https://nam06.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.linkedin.com%2Fhelp%2Flinkedin%2Fask%2Fppq&data=05%7C02%7Cssundholm%40linkedin.com%7Cda78086e62bc43d9651708dcc759ec40%7C72f988bf86f141af91ab2d7cd011db47%7C0%7C0%7C638604436264149657%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C0%7C%7C%7C&sdata=KFnKedvcckZE6sfyxXqL%2FjkCdzKxwi%2B5WmejCVGH3Lk%3D&reserved=0). When you withdraw your consent, this won’t affect our use of your data up to that point.

#### **Joint Controller Relationship**

We share insights with entities who have LinkedIn Business Pages on our platform, which include certain Member profile information and interaction data. We are a joint controller with the organisation or legal entity who administers the Business Page for this purpose, and Members can find out more information about LinkedIn’s responsibilities [here](https://legal.linkedin.com/pages-joint-controller-addendum).

#### **Data Retention**

We generally retain your personal data as long as you keep your account open or as needed to provide you Services. This includes data you or others provided to us and data generated or inferred from your use of our Services. Even if you only use our Services when looking for a new job every few years, we will retain your information and keep your profile open, unless you close your account. In some cases we choose to retain certain information (e.g., insights about Services use) in a depersonalised or aggregated form.   

You can [delete data from your profile or your activity](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1342613) on LinkedIn. If you close your account with LinkedIn, it is closed immediately. However, it may take up to 72 hours for your public profile to be removed from LinkedIn. Search engines like Bing, Google and Yahoo! may still display your information temporarily due to the way they collect and update their search data. Learn more about [how your profile shows up in search engine results](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1376045/). Where we share your data with other third parties, as set out in our [Privacy Policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy), e.g. via the LinkedIn Developer Program, they may retain data in accordance with their own retention policies, or in line with our contractual agreements with them.   

For data that LinkedIn collects using cookies, you can see how long LinkedIn processes it for by checking the expiration periods in our [Cookie table](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/l/cookie-table). LinkedIn may also collect information about you from cookies on third party websites. For data collected from third party websites where a LinkedIn customer has installed LinkedIn’s tag, LinkedIn de-identifies your personal data after 7 days and permanently deletes it after 180 days.  

There are a number of reasons why we might need to retain some of your data for longer than usual. These may include:

*   Where LinkedIn has suspended your account for inappropriate, harmful or illegal activity that breaches our Professional Community Guidelines and/or we need to resolve complaints relating to your account.
*   Where there is ongoing or potential legal or regulatory proceedings related to your account.
*   Where we are required by law to retain your data. For more information on when we may be required to retain your data for these purposes, see the “**Compliance with Legal Obligations**” section above.  

#### **Transfers of your data outside the Designated Countries and the UK** 

LinkedIn may transfer personal data outside of the Designated Countries and the UK as part of its Services e.g. LinkedIn stores personal data on its servers located in the US, so data flows from the EU, EEA, United Kingdom and Switzerland to the US, and back. LinkedIn will always use a lawful transfer mechanism to transfer your data outside of the Designated Countries including transfers based on an adequacy decision by an approved authority, standard contractual clauses or, where appropriate, derogations permitted by law.   

LinkedIn is certified to the EU-U.S. Data Privacy Framework, the UK Extension to the EU-U.S. Data Privacy Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Data Privacy Framework, and you can find out more information about our participation in the Data Privacy Framework [here](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a1343190).  

LinkedIn also relies on the European Commission-approved Standard Contractual Clauses for transfers of certain personal data from the EU/EEA and Switzerland and on the UK Data Transfer Addendum for certain transfers from the UK. These clauses are contractual commitments between companies (e.g. between LinkedIn Ireland Unlimited Company and LinkedIn Corporation or suppliers). You can request a copy of LinkedIn’s Standard Contractual clauses [here](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/ask/ppq).

#### **Contacting your Supervisory Authority**

If you have a concern or complaint about the use of your personal data that you feel has not been addressed by us, you always have the right to raise a concern with the supervisory authority in your jurisdiction.

#### **Contact Us**

If you have a question about our practices or your choices, you can reach us in the following ways:

#### **Online:**

LinkedIn online support can be contacted using this [form](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/ask/ppq)**,** or [live chat](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/solve) for Members.

#### **By Mail:**  

If you are in the Designated Countries: 

℅ Data Protection Officer 

LinkedIn Ireland Unlimited Company  

Wilton Plaza 

Dublin 2 

Ireland   

﻿If you are in the UK: 

℅ Data Protection Officer 

1000 W Maude Avenue 

Sunnyvale

CA   

#### **Data Protection Officer:**

Our Data Protection Officer can be contacted directly using this [form](https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/ask/TSO-DPO).
